Layton Avery

Software Developer Atlanta, Georgia

laytonavery5@gmail.com · <u>linkedin.com/in/laytonavery</u> · <u>https://github.com/</u> LaytonAvery

Project-focused software developer at DigitalCrafts with anticipated graduation on May 20, 2021. Specializes in utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Express, Node, and MongoDB to build mobile-responsive websites from scratch. Strengths include adaptability, exceptional communication, effective problem- solving, and time management. Extremely detail-oriented due to years of experience in healthcare.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Python, React/Redux, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap, MongoDB, MySQL

Education

- Software Engineering Immersive, DigitalCrafts—Feb 2021-present
- BS Cardiorespiratory Science, *University of South Alabama*—Aug 2015-May 2017
 - BA Biology, Troy University—Aug 2011-May 2015

Experience

Software Engineering Immersive

Feb 2021-Present

• Develop multiple mobile-responsive web applications in software engineering training course covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript and Python, with an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node, Express, and MongoDB.

Respiratory Therapist

Jan 2016-Jan 2021

- Created patient care plans based on patient assessment with the goal of improving patients' quality of life; Provided patient education and teaching.
- Managed ventilator therapy; monitored and documented physiological responses to medications and therapy via EMR software such as EPIC, Cerner, and Allscripts Sunrise.

Current Projects

Pharmaci May 2021

• Designed application that generates fictional pharmaceutical names for medications at the click of a button. Built with Javascript, Node, Express, MySQL, React Bootstrap, and React.

<u>DaintyDesignz</u> May 2021

• Building an ecommerce site with user authentication, fully functional checkout process, and admin screens. Building with Javascript, React/Redux, Node, Express & MongoDB.